<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Portfolio]]></title><description><![CDATA[A starter blog demonstrating what Gatsby can do.]]></description><link>https://jsdario.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 12:40:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Scope 🔬]]></title><description><![CDATA[Scope was a tool created in Yeti Smart Home to be able to measure the impact of
each developer in the start-up. Later, it has been taken…]]></description><link>https://jsdario.github.io/scope/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jsdario.github.io/scope/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Scope was a tool created in Yeti Smart Home to be able to measure the impact of
each developer in the start-up. Later, it has been taken over by a group of passionate
friends to make a company of it with the mission of “Measure Creative Work”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://scope.ink&quot;&gt;https://scope.ink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chaos Pad]]></title><description><![CDATA[With the intention or recreating via software the electronic pad embedded on
Matt Bellamy’s (MUSE) guitar that enables him to transform the…]]></description><link>https://jsdario.github.io/chaos-pad/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jsdario.github.io/chaos-pad/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;With the intention or recreating via software the electronic pad embedded on
Matt Bellamy’s (MUSE) guitar that enables him to transform the outbound sound
wave into something out of the bounds of a guitar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jsdario.github.io/chaos&quot;&gt;https://jsdario.github.io/chaos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lengua Materna]]></title><description><![CDATA[Writing in English is not an easy decision. In Medium I have followers mainly
for the Engineering+Product content that I write in English or…]]></description><link>https://jsdario.github.io/the-language/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jsdario.github.io/the-language/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Writing in English is not an easy decision. In Medium I have followers mainly
for the Engineering+Product content that I write in English or my essays and articles in Spanish. That way is very difficult to mantain a consistent publication strategy (and I don’t intend to), here I will have probably have less
restrictions so I will be able to keep pieces in whatever language I am more
comfortable writing for that topic. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jsdariorivera&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; I suffer the same dicotomy. Having this site will –all likely– allow me to definitely switch between both languages to only one in a hypothetical future where that decision matters at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funny enough, in English my words spread faster and further, but in Spanish my
words resonate deeper within the smaller network. This is all likely a “problem”
shared by many authors and entrepreneurs in the digital era. I have no intention
to choose, but if there is a preferred strategy, I’d probably choose deeper than
wider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These words above about this site and its purpose are more for my future self
than for you; In any case, hope you find it interesting. I will use this way
my public voice to order my own thoughs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Purpose]]></title><description><![CDATA[I decided to –finally– open a site about myself. I never really consider doing
it. Partly because I thought it was best to let facts and…]]></description><link>https://jsdario.github.io/purpose/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jsdario.github.io/purpose/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I decided to –finally– open a site about myself. I never really consider doing
it. Partly because I thought it was best to let facts and projects speak by
themselves. However, as time passed by, I find it increasingly important to
remind yourself about the things you have accomplish. With two objectives: (1) to
serve as motivation to keep working in the things you love and (2) so those
projects are not forgotten, or are better taken care of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose to open a static site (using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/&quot;&gt;Gatsby&lt;/a&gt;) because the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am already familiar with the technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I find Markdown the best format to write posts in a minimal way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimalism makes thing preserve in time, removing part of the fatigue of
seeing the same things over and over&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A static site can be delivered in a very fast fashion by a number of free services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s flexible enough to allow me play with low-level browser APIs and brind smalls samples of my past work to interactive pieces in this very site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last point is specially important since a heavy part of the things I want
to showcase are not finite things but living projects; My coding activity; The
latest version to a certain app; A visualization of a certain state. All those
are things that &lt;em&gt;change&lt;/em&gt; through time, and I need access to &lt;em&gt;code&lt;/em&gt; to better
portray those realities in a single article. That is impossible for me to do
in most platforms (Tumblr, Medium &amp;#x26; alike) and so the only way to achieve it
is to fork my own system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no interest in update this site super frequently, but rather when there
is something that I want to share worth showcasing. I am a very eclectic person,
so rather than publishing blog entries, I’ll keep &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jsdario&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;
as the platform where I write and develop ideas, and keep entries here simple
enough to understand what has been done.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>